# Mostafa Fouad El-Sayed Ragab

Sheikh Zayed city · Egypt E-mail: m.f.ragab5890@gmail.com

LinkedIn: <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/mostafa-fouad-ragab">https://www.linkedin.com/in/mostafa-fouad-ragab</a>

GitHub: <a href="https://github.com/mfragab5890">https://github.com/mfragab5890</a>
Cell phone: +2 01122221136
+2 01111206636

## PERSONAL STATEMENT

I want to invest my experience as a web developer with my years of experience as an industrial engineer in which I gained my problem-solving skills, data analysis, scientific thinking, team working, my passion for continuous development to be part of a team that contributes to building the future in a reputable company that aims to excellence and accomplish achievements.

## **EMPLOYMENT HISTORY**

- Freelance.
  - Full-stack Developer.

Jan 2019 – present.

- Ceramica Prima (Part of E.G.M.I group).
  - Production department manager.
  - > Assistant production manager.
  - Production engineer.
  - R&D engineer.

June 2014 – present. (July 2017- present).

(September 2016 – June 2017).

(March 2015 - September 2015).

(June 2014 - March 2015).

- Skam International Plastic Co.
  - > Industrial engineer.

**September 2013 – June 2014.** 

### **EDUCATION**

- Alexandria University, Faculty of Engineering, Industrial Department [2012-2013]
  - Grade: "Good".
    - Graduation Project: Simulation modeling of the industrial process in CARGILL Co. using arena software [2013]
       Grade "Excellent".
- Secondary school: Zahran Language School [2006-2007].

## **CERTIFICATES & COURSES.**

Web Development Advanced Nanodegree.

Udacity (Dec 2020).

"Master SQL & postgres and Data Modeling for the web, and learn how to use APIs to control and manage web applications, including best practices for API testing and documentation, in this degree I used (Python, Flask, Postgres, Flask-SQLAlchemy, Flask-Migrate, Rest API, Unittest, Flask-CORS, Auth0, postman)".

Agile with Atlassian Jira.

Coursera (October 2020).

"This course discusses common foundational principles and practices used by agile and lean principles, the kanban and scrum agile methodologies, and uses Atlassian Jira Software Cloud as the main software tool to apply hands-on learning of the topics. The course includes instruction on "classic" Jira projects as well as the new "next-gen" Jira projects.".

Web Development Professional Nanodegree.

Udacity (Sept 2020).

"advanced JavaScript, Dom methods and how to work with APIs. to be able to add interactivity and different services to website and make it more engaging and alive, in this degree I used (Asynchronous JavaScript, node js, express js, web APIs)".

#### Data analysis challenger.

Udacity (July 2020).

"data analysis process of questioning, wrangling, exploring, analyzing, and communicating data".

#### Web development, HTLM, CSS, JavaScript & Git.

IBM Digital-Nation (April 2020).

#### ■ The complete JavaScript course.

Udemy (march 2019).

#### Git& GitHub for beginners.

Traversy media (June 2018).

Complete web development (HTML – CSS – Bootstrap – JavaScript – jQuery – php – MySQL).
 Udemy (Jan 2018).

#### Embedded Systems Diploma.

Arab Academy for Science and Technology. (June 2017)

"Embedded systems interfacing, C programming, communication protocols (UART, SPI, I2C), Data structures, RTOS, testing, Autosar overview".

## LANGUAGES:

Arabic: Mother tongue.

English: Excellent.

French: Basic.

German: Basic (undergoing).

## **SKILLS:**

HTML.

CSS.

Bootstrap.

JavaScript.

Node JS.

Express JS.

jQuery.

Python.

Flask

PostgreSQL

JIRA – basic.Rest APIs.

MySQL.

C programming.

# **PROJECTS**

#### Weather journal App.

"web app that get weather data of user entered zip code and take hi note post it to server then retrieve latest entry and dynamically update web app- <a href="https://github.com/mfragab5890/weather-journal-app.git/">https://github.com/mfragab5890/weather-journal-app.git/</a> - <a href="https://weather-api-journal.herokuapp.com/">https://weather-api-journal.herokuapp.com/</a>"

- Landing Page Sample.
- "landing page sample using HTML, CSS and JavaScript <a href="https://landing-page-2021.herokuapp.com/">https://landing-page-2021.herokuapp.com/</a> <a href="https://github.com/mfragab5890/landing-page.git/">https://github.com/mfragab5890/landing-page.git/</a> "
- fashion show reservation web app.

"I fully developed this project and the customer only gave requirements and design vision.

-https://fashion-show.herokuapp.com/ - https://github.com/mfragab5890/cairo-events"

sending and receiving work order web app

"I fully developed this project to send/receive/display/update work orders for national Egyptian TV. <a href="https://maspero.herokuapp.com/">https://maspero.herokuapp.com/</a> - <a href="https://github.com/mfragab5890/Egypt-tv-work-order.git">https://github.com/mfragab5890/Egypt-tv-work-order.git</a>"

#### Temperature monitoring system.

"microcontroller that takes temperature sensor reading and send it to server while web app handles the results and send alerts in case of emergency- https://github.com/mfragab5890/temprature-monitoring-system.git/"

#### Industrial palletizer.

"A machine that get the packed product from a belt and choose where to place it according to the sorting grade no. of product and layer on the pallet- https://github.com/mfragab5890/industrial-palletizer.git/"

> I was responsible to develop the whole code using cx programmer.